# Xiaowei (Ellen) Wang

42D, Tower 6, The Long Beach, 8 Hoi Fai Road, Hong Kong xiaowei0130@gmail.com | +852 6762 2495

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Certified Public Accountant with 3 years of experience of corporate tax advisory, planning and compliance, and analysis of business performance enhancement. Leveraging on my accounting and finance expertise and experience, I am ready to embark on my next career.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ernst & Young Hong Kong

Senior Accountant, Tax & Business Advisory Services

09/2013 - 04/2017

- Prepare Chinese and English research report and briefing notes of up-to-date accounting policies and tax regulations
- Optimize financial analysis and data analysis using spreadsheet pivot tables
- Develop higher-level tax data review for Audited Financial Statements preparations
- Design tailor-made advice for multinational corporations to improve effectiveness of tax structure
- Advise clients on correspondence from tax authorities

## **Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu**

Hong Kong

Summer Intern, Global Employer Services, Tax Department

06/2012 - 08/2012

- Analyzed corporate compensation and allowance structures and delivered a cost-effective restructure plan to the senior management
- Drafted global key accounts' individual tax returns from the ground up, with tax reporting experience

#### **EDUCATION**

## The University of Hong Kong

**Hong Kong** 

*Master of Finance (Part-time)* 

2016 - Present

- Cumulative GPA: 3.77, Corporate Finance stream
- Main Courses: Corporate Finance and Asset Valuation, Economics for Financial Analysis, Economics, Investment Analysis and Portfolio Management, Derivative Securities, Fund Management and Alternative Investments, Business Intelligence and Big Data

# **City University of Hong Kong**

Hong Kong

Bachelor of Business Administration (Honours) in Accountancy (Full-time)

2009 - 2012

- Cumulative GPA: 3.64 (Dean's list: four semesters), First Class Honours
- Main Courses: Financial Management, Corporate Financial Strategy, Economics, Statistics, Managerial Accounting, Corporate Accounting, Auditing, Taxation System, Financial Reporting Theory
- **Scholarships**: Mainland Student Scholarship First Class (320,000 HKD, only offered to the top 0.5% students); Outstanding Performance Scholarship (30,000 HKD)
- Awards: Chartered Institute of Management Accountants Prize Winner by CIMA; member of Alpha Beta Gamma
- **Professional certification:** HKICPA (January 2017)

# SKILLS, ACTIVITIES & DATE OF AVAILABILITY

**Computing:** MS Office, Thomson Reuters ONESOURCE, Bloomberg, Adobe Photoshop,

Word of Science, Lotus Notes, Capital IQ, SNL Financial, Factiva

**Languages:** Trilingual in English, Cantonese, and Mandarin (ILETS: 7.0)

**Certifications:** Passed CFA Level I Exam (01/2016)

**Activities:** Golden Z Club, CityU Student Union (2009 – 2010, regular voluntary elderly cares)

Consultant on Professional Writing (2011 - 2013, university level English writing consultation) Editor, City Literary Festival (2011, interviewed Mr. ZHENG Chouyu and co-edited a book)

**Availability:** April 2017 **Expected salaries:** Negotiable